<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-Gators</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on R-Gators</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Loops in R</title>
      <link>/2017/10/25/loops-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/25/loops-in-r/</guid>
      <description>link to data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data manipulation in the tidyverse</title>
      <link>/2017/09/27/data-manipulation-in-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/27/data-manipulation-in-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>link to R script</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Dataframes in R </title>
      <link>/2017/09/06/introduction-to-dataframes-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/06/introduction-to-dataframes-in-r/</guid>
      <description>link to pdf
 Reading CSV datafiles into R We often store our data in comma seperated value (CSV) files, which can be read into R using the read.csv() function:
# Download example .csv file download.file(&amp;quot;https://ndownloader.figshare.com/files/2292169&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;data/portal_data_joined.csv&amp;quot;) # Save into variable surveys &amp;lt;- read.csv(&#39;data/portal_data_joined.csv&#39;)  Note: this code requires having a data/ folder in your project
Functions for characterizing dataframe We can run the name of the variable to view the dataframe, but often there will be too much information to display in the console</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R and RStudio</title>
      <link>/2017/08/30/introduction-to-r-and-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/30/introduction-to-r-and-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>link to pdf
 Links  Etherpad notes Data Carpentry R lesson Download R Download RStudio  Why R?  R doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve pointing and clicking Great for reproducibility Works for all sorts of data Creating awesome graphics Interdisplincary with a large community Free, open-source, and cross-platform  RStudio RStudio is a free Integrated Development Environment (IDE) for working with R
This provides a framework for:
 Writing code Navigating files Visualizing packages Creating projects Many other goodies (version control, making packages, Shiny apps)  RStudio Projects Projects in RStudio create a folder for storing all of our files (data, scripts, images)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speeding up R code using Rcpp and foreach packages</title>
      <link>/2017/02/08/speeding-up-r-code-using-rcpp-and-foreach-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/08/speeding-up-r-code-using-rcpp-and-foreach-packages/</guid>
      <description>Download a pdf of Dr. Albuquerque&amp;rsquo;s presentation here.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Meeting Presentation: Rcpp and foreach</title>
      <link>/2017/02/02/upcoming-meeting-presentation-rcpp-and-foreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/02/upcoming-meeting-presentation-rcpp-and-foreach/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the details for this week&amp;rsquo;s R meetup session:
Presentation: &amp;ldquo;Speeding up R code using Rcpp and foreach packages&amp;rdquo; by Dr Pedro Albuquerque Time: 4 to 6pm Date: Feb 8 (Wednesday) Venue: Marston Science Library Room L136
We think this week&amp;rsquo;s presentation topic will be very useful for those of us who have (or planning to write) R codes take up lots of computing power and time. By leveraging on C++, via Rcpp, and package such as foreach, it is possible to get your job done faster!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses at UF</title>
      <link>/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/</guid>
      <description>Workshops The Software and Data Carpentry workshops are a great way to jump-start your R programming skills. Workshops are offered regularly across campus, check out the UF Informatics Institute website for upcoming workshops.
Also, all of the course materials are freely available at any time, so you can work through these lessons on your own. The Data Analysis and Visualization in R is a great place to start, and the Programming with R and R for Reproducible Scientific Analysis lessons provide more in-depth resources for mastering R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People and Resources</title>
      <link>/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributors/</guid>
      <description>About the people and the resources.
UF Informatics Institute UF Libraries Denis Valle Lab R Social Sciences Interest group (R-SSIG) R-SSIG is a group of faculty and graduate students in the social sciences from different departments across UF. Their goal is to coordinate social science faculty and students who can help each other to effectively learn R, and to focus on the most appropriate R facilities for their kind of research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/schedule/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starter&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/start/</guid>
      <description>Installing R and RStudio  The first step is to install R, just select the correct link for your operating system
 Next, we highly recommend installing RStudio. This is an &amp;ldquo;integrated development environment&amp;rdquo; (IDE), which provides a useful interface from programming in R. It&amp;rsquo;s not essential, but it will make your life easier (especially for beginnings), and it&amp;rsquo;s free!
 You&amp;rsquo;re ready to start programming in R! Now you can sign up for the UF R list-serv, take a look at the schedule for activities on campus, and check out the R-related courses and workshops at UF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UF R List-Serv</title>
      <link>/listserv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/listserv/</guid>
      <description>We have resurrected the UF R list-serv to provide a forum for asking questions in R. Please sign up for the list-serv here. If you want to manage how you recieve emails from the list, follow this link. Sign in and change setting under the subscriber&amp;rsquo;s corner. We strive to make the list beginner-friendly, however please check out this posting guide before posting (well-formmated questions can be answered much quicker!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Meetups</title>
      <link>/meetups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meetups/</guid>
      <description>Our weekly meetups are on Wednesdays from 4-6pm at the Marstons Science Library (located here). The meetups consist of presentation/tutorial covering interesting topics in R, and are followed by an open session where you can consult advanced R users. Please be sure to sign up for the list-serv for updates on topics and changes to the schedule/locations.
If you have suggestions for future presentations, or are interested in giving a presentation (even better!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>