<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on R-Gators</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on R-Gators</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Species Distribution Models</title>
      <link>/2018/01/24/introduction-to-species-distribution-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/24/introduction-to-species-distribution-models/</guid>
      <description>Check out Dr. Zhao’s presentation: http://www.r-gators.com/slides/zhao. This presentation was made using RMarkdown. The Markdown code is included below, however outputs from R (i.e. graphs) will only be displayed in the presentation.
Download the RMarkdown file and an R script for generating data to test these scripts at the GitHub repository: https://github.com/ufrmeetup/zhao. Note the RMarkdown script relies on some private data, so it will not run on it’s own, but can be run using the simulated data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-validation</title>
      <link>/2017/11/29/cross-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/29/cross-validation/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will be talking about the importance of cross-validation to choose the best model. To do this, we will show:
the problem of using simple in-sample metrics for model selection with a univariate examplethe problem of using simple in-sample metrics for model selection with a multivariable examplehow to perform cross-validation using simple linear regression and some problems associated with this1) The problem of using simple in-sample metrics for model seelction with a univariate exampleWhen dealing with a regression model, we are often interested in determining which covariates to keep in the model and which to through away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping in R exercise</title>
      <link>/2017/11/15/mapping-in-r-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/15/mapping-in-r-exercise/</guid>
      <description>link to folder</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RMarkdown and bookdown</title>
      <link>/2017/11/01/rmarkdown-and-bookdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/01/rmarkdown-and-bookdown/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is an introductory post into using Bookdown. Bookdown is a powerful package that allows you to create documents embedding images, tables, and code. One great reason to use Bookdown is that you can put results and images from your code directly into your text, which reduces the chances of copying errors. For this post, I’m going to focus on creating an HTML document, though you can also create outputs in Word and PDF formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loops in R</title>
      <link>/2017/10/25/loops-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/25/loops-in-r/</guid>
      <description>link to data
  Introduction to using for loops What Are Loops? “Looping”, “cycling”, “iterating” or just replicating instructions is an old practice that originated well before the invention of computers. It is nothing more than automating a multi-step process by organizing sequences of actions or ‘batch’ processes and by grouping the parts that need to be repeated. All modern programming languages provide special constructs that allow for the repetition of instructions or blocks of instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating functions in R</title>
      <link>/2017/10/18/creating-functions-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/18/creating-functions-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Download pdf
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data manipulation in the tidyverse</title>
      <link>/2017/09/27/data-manipulation-in-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/27/data-manipulation-in-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>link to R script</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Dataframes in R </title>
      <link>/2017/09/06/introduction-to-dataframes-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/06/introduction-to-dataframes-in-r/</guid>
      <description>link to pdf
 Reading CSV datafiles into R We often store our data in comma seperated value (CSV) files, which can be read into R using the read.csv() function:
# Download example .csv file download.file(&amp;quot;https://ndownloader.figshare.com/files/2292169&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;data/portal_data_joined.csv&amp;quot;) # Save into variable surveys &amp;lt;- read.csv(&#39;data/portal_data_joined.csv&#39;)  Note: this code requires having a data/ folder in your project
Functions for characterizing dataframe We can run the name of the variable to view the dataframe, but often there will be too much information to display in the console</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R and RStudio</title>
      <link>/2017/08/30/introduction-to-r-and-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/30/introduction-to-r-and-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>link to pdf
 Links  Etherpad notes Data Carpentry R lesson Download R Download RStudio  Why R?  R doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve pointing and clicking Great for reproducibility Works for all sorts of data Creating awesome graphics Interdisplincary with a large community Free, open-source, and cross-platform  RStudio RStudio is a free Integrated Development Environment (IDE) for working with R
This provides a framework for:
 Writing code Navigating files Visualizing packages Creating projects Many other goodies (version control, making packages, Shiny apps)  RStudio Projects Projects in RStudio create a folder for storing all of our files (data, scripts, images)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speeding up R code using Rcpp and foreach packages</title>
      <link>/2017/02/08/speeding-up-r-code-using-rcpp-and-foreach-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/08/speeding-up-r-code-using-rcpp-and-foreach-packages/</guid>
      <description>Download a pdf of Dr. Albuquerque&amp;rsquo;s presentation here.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Meeting Presentation: Rcpp and foreach</title>
      <link>/2017/02/02/upcoming-meeting-presentation-rcpp-and-foreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/02/upcoming-meeting-presentation-rcpp-and-foreach/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the details for this week&amp;rsquo;s R meetup session:
Presentation: &amp;ldquo;Speeding up R code using Rcpp and foreach packages&amp;rdquo; by Dr Pedro Albuquerque Time: 4 to 6pm Date: Feb 8 (Wednesday) Venue: Marston Science Library Room L136
We think this week&amp;rsquo;s presentation topic will be very useful for those of us who have (or planning to write) R codes take up lots of computing power and time. By leveraging on C++, via Rcpp, and package such as foreach, it is possible to get your job done faster!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>